<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>meredrica&#39;s ramblings</title>
  
  <link href="/hexo-theme-material-image/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
  <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>meredrica</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Kurzgeschichte: Mr. Ego
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/09/11/Kurzgeschichte-Mr-Ego/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/09/11/Kurzgeschichte-Mr-Ego/</id>
    <published>2016-09-11T20:24:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Eine kleine Kurzgeschichte welche mir am Heimweg aus Berlin eingefallen ist und sofort niedergeschrieben werden musste. Enjoy.</em></p><p>“Lass es doch einfach!” sage ich. Schon wieder. Seit einer gefühlten Ewigkeit versuche ich nun diesen Idioten von seinem Trip runter zu holen. Ich habe ihm jetzt zig Mal erklärt dass das keine gute Idee ist, dass das hier niemand braucht und niemandem hilft. Mir nicht und ihm ganz sicher auch nicht. Vergebens.</p><p>Plötzlich ändert sich seine Körperspannung. War ja klar, er kann es nicht lassen. Ich habe jetzt lange genug versucht das zu vermeiden, meine Geduld ist nun zu Ende. Meine Optionen ebenfalls, die hat Mr. Ego gerade höchstpersönlich vernichtet. Na gut, dann eben so.</p><p>Mein Verstand nimmt sich zurück, er vertraut meinem Körper. Meine Sinne arbeiten um ein vielfaches schneller als sonst. In jeder anderen Situation würde mein Geist jetzt heillos im Information Overkill landen und absolut paralysiert sein. Aber nicht jetzt, nicht hier. Das wäre wirklich nicht besonders Zielführend und außerdem auch scheiß Gefährlich. Aber bevor alles im Chaos von zu vielen Informationen untergeht passiert noch etwas ganz Anderes. Programm Ü wird ausgelöst. Keine Diskussion, kein Aber. Phase eins beginnt.</p><p>Erstmal wird gerade alles neu verdrahtet. Input und Output sind fast direkt miteinander gekoppelt. Dazwischen nur Filter und Reflexe. Genau für solche Situationen sind unmengen an Möglichkeiten bereits gelöst, interpretiert und verbessert. Überraschungen sind zwar immer Möglich, aber unwahrscheinlich. Sollte eine auf mich zukommen wird sie auf dieser Ebene gelöst, ein minimaler Zeitunterschied anstelle der gespeicherten Lösung, kaum der Rede wert.<br>Das Bewusstsein ist nur Zuseher. Zu Analysezwecken.</p><p>Der Plan wird weiter ausgeführt. Phase 2: Scan. Im Bruchteil eines Bruchteils einer Sekunde wird erstmal Information gesammelt. Meinen Geist arbeitet wie auf einer Überdosis Speed, nur bin ich nicht high. Zum Glück bin ich nicht ganz bei Bewusstsein, das wäre wirklich anstrengend. Der installierte Filter aus Phase 1 funktioniert einwandfrei. Nur keine unwichtigen Details jetzt. Dafür alles andere und viel davon.<br>Mr. Ego ist sofort fertig analysiert. Positionen aller notwendigen Punkte sind sofort erfasst, stellung im Raum ebenso. Gefahrenpotentiale sind erkannt, kategorisiert und nach dringlichkeit geordnet.<br>Der nächste Scan beginnt sofort. Selbstanalyse. Halbwegs zufrieden beendet die Ü Programmierung die Selbsterkenntnis. Verbesserungswürdig aber brauchbar. Das muss besser werden. Meldung darüber an den Geist wird sofort gemacht, aber der hat jetzt nur zuzuhören. Bis der jetzt reagiert ist es zu spät.</p><p>Weiter mit Plan Ü. Phase drei: Action.<br>Alle Informationen sind geladen, Daten über die Umwelt liegen vor. Das muss reichen. Was nun passiert ist am Eigenartigsten. Der Grund warum das Hirn dem Computer immer noch überlegen ist passiert genau hier, auf dieser Ebene. Aus der unendlich großen Mengen an Möglichkeiten wird die beste ausgewählt, ganz ohne Zeitverzögerung. Beeindruckend schnell, ohne großen Aufwand. Wenn wir das nur könnten.<br>Programm Ü fackelt nicht lange. Dafür wurde es ja auch mühsam über Jahre hinweg angelegt und trainiert. Jetzt darf es mal endlich machen.</p><p>Und das tut es auch. Und wie.<br>Die geladenen Informationen werden direkt in Realität übersetzt. Einige Details dazu werde ich nach der ganzen Situation vergessen haben. Mein Gegenüber allerdings nicht.<br>Der output Kanal befindet sich im Dauerfeuer. In solchen Situationen wird die Aufnahmekapazität der Nerven einfach kurzzeitig vergrößert. Auch etwas das uns der eigene Körper voraus hat.<br>Der Rest des Körpers gehorcht sofort. Bewegungen welche tausende male bereits ausgeführt werden laufen nun endlich mal in maximaler Geschwindigkeit an. Mein Körper freut sich.</p><p>Mr. Ego ist dabei auszuholen. Selbst schuld, das war sein Fehler. Programm Ü zu triggern ist einfach keine gute Idee. Außerdem hat der Geist gerade kein Recht und auch keine Möglichkeit einzugreifen. Zurück gibt es nicht.<br>Vorwärts, auf in den Kampf. Normale Menschen laufen nicht zur Gefahr. Ich aber schon, dort ist es sicher. Ein paradoxes Gesetz welches ich schon lange nicht mehr hinterfrage.<br>Mr. Ego hat damit offensichtlich ein konzeptionelles Problem, aber das fällt ihm jetzt zu spät auf. Aus dem Nichts erscheint mein Arm und stellt sich ihm in den Weg, lange vor dem Kontakt. Keine Ahnung woher der gekommen ist, die Konzentration liegt beim zweiten Arm. Meine Körpermitte ist schon längst am Weg nach unten und vorne. Die halb geschlossene Hand überholt den Rest, beschleunigt durch das Drehmoment aus den Hüften.<br>Aber das ist kein Angriff. Hier kommt nur der Schock. Die Hand berührt den Rumpf meines Gegenübers knapp unter dem Rippenbogen, etwas auf der linken Seite. Perfekt. Das Auftreffen ist für mich nur ein kleiner Kontakt, als würde man in die Hände klatschen. Mr. Ego sieht das allerdings anders.</p><p>Schockiert durch den unerwarteten Treffer und dessen Wucht beginnt er sich nach vorne zu Krümmen. Perfekte Reaktion, genau das sollte ja auch passieren. Hand nummer zwei hat schon längst zugegriffen, ein Reflex der noch tiefer als Programm Ü sitzt. Meine Körperbewegung wird von meinen Beinen automatisch in einen Halbkreis verwandelt. Die Jacke hindert mich etwas, ein weiterer Punkt für die ToDo Liste des Geistes. Der Griff sitzt nicht perfekt aber dafür sehr fest. Ready to rock, locked and loaded. Mit der Drehung kommt der Schmerz. Ich weiß das aus jahrelanger Erfahrung. Mein Gegenüber auch bald, nur muss er die Erfahrung wesentlich schneller machen.</p><p>Wenn das Gelenk eines Menschen unter mechanischer Einwirkung zu sperren beginnt hat das ein ganz eigenes Feeling. Man spürt das Gefühl des anderen, seinen Schmerz und seine Toleranz dessen. Das ist gut, damit kann man arbeiten. Mr. Ego hier braucht einen Reality Check. Ich bin mir nur nicht sicher ob er das so vor hatte. Aber das hat er sich selbst eingebrockt.<br>Ich drehe mich und bemerke wie sich die Spannung in seinem Handgelenk und Unterarm vergrößert. Der Punkt an dem er Schmerzen empfindet ist bereits überschritten. Programm Ü wechselt noch einmal kurz in Phase 2 während sich mein Körper nach meinem Zeitempfinden in Slow Motion bewegt. Nach der Analyse steht das weitere Schicksal von Mr. Ego fest. Er wird es wohl überleben, wenn auch mit einiger Zeit Reha. Das Gelenk blockiert nun endgültig. Das Gleichgewicht war schon zum Zeitpunkt meiner Vorwärtsbewegung gebrochen, alles weitere übernimmt die Physik. Gravity is a ruthless Bitch.</p><p>Mr. Ego kippt nach hinten. Schlag nummer Zwei ist schon unterwegs, wäre jedoch gar nicht mehr nötig. Egal, das aufzuhalten wäre nur Mühsam. Die omnipräsente Schlagwaffe namens Erde kann man nicht verfehlen. Damit der Idiot das ganze halbwegs unbeschadet übersteht Bremse ich seinen Fall ein wenig ab. Der Aufschlag ist dennoch keine angenehme Erfahrung für ihn. Das ist nicht nur offensichtlich sondern auch deutlich zu Hören.</p><p>Programm Ü beschließt sich zurück zu ziehen. Auf dem Rückzug feuert es jedoch nochmals zwei Befehle ab, nur so zur Sicherheit. Befehl Eins endet mit einem sehr unsanftem Auftreffen meines Fußballens auf seiner rechten Niere. Eine Bewegung welche mein Körper schon so oft durchgeführt hat dass sie nicht einmal mehr vom Programm Ü wahrgenommen wird. Nummer zwei geht nahtlos daraus hervor. Mr. Ego hat nun auch noch einige sehr schmerzende Rippen und eine unnatürliche Stellung des Handgelenks zu verarbeiten. Gut so.</p><p>Mein Bewusstsein bekommt die Entscheidungsgewalt zurück. Programm beendet, alles Easy, alles unter Kontrolle.<br>Der Kontextwechsel dauert ein paar Augenblicke in denen mein Bewusstsein damit beschäftigt ist zu verstehen wie der Körper in dieser Situation gelandet ist und was nun zu tun ist. Aufarbeitung wird auf später verschoben. Erst mal muss Geklärt werden wie es jetzt weiter geht.</p><p>“Ich hab dir doch gesagt du sollst mich in Ruhe lassen. Was sollte der Scheiß?”<br>Nach ein paar Momenten, in denen sich Mr. Ego sammelt, verlautbart er mit einem großzügigen Maß an Arroganz:<br>“Leck mich doch du verdammte Schlampe! Dir werde ich gleich zeigen was es heißt zu mir Nein zu sagen! Dein Arsch gehört mir!”.<br>Aha, einer der es einfach nicht kapieren will. Ich habe aber mein Bestes bereits gegeben und habe jetzt keine Nachsicht mehr. Die Stellung des Handgelänks wird spürbar unnatürlicher. Mr. Ego reagiert darauf mit Gegenwehr. Jetzt reicht es aber.<br>“Also Gut, dann eben so.” säufze ich. Ein kurzer Ruck, ich stehe auf und blicke zu Boden. Unter mir spielt sich ein kleines Drama ab. Mr. Ego hat eine sehr ungesund wirkende Hautfarbe angenommen und versucht vergeblich seinen Arm in einer Position zu halten die nicht schmerzhaft ist. Seine Schulter wirkt etwas deplaziert und unförmig. Er ist auf einmal sehr laut geworden.</p><p>Wärend eine endlose Tirade an Schmerzensschreien und Wimmern auf mich einprasselt stehe ich auf. Mein Geist beginnt bereits die Aufarbeitung zu planen, lässt sich aber noch Zeit. Ich ziehe meinen Minirock gerade, richte meine Frisur, ärgere mich über den abgebrochenen Absatz und verlasse die kleine Gasse neben der Bar.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eine kleine Kurzgeschichte welche mir am Heimweg aus Berlin eingefallen ist und sofort niedergeschrieben werden musste. Enjoy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Lass es doch einfach!” sage ich. Schon wieder. Seit einer gefühlten Ewigkeit versuche ich nun diesen Idioten von seinem Trip runter zu holen. Ich habe ihm jetzt zig Mal erklärt dass das keine gute Idee ist, dass das hier niemand braucht und niemandem hilft. Mir nicht und ihm ganz sicher auch nicht. Vergebens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plötzlich ändert sich seine Körperspannung. War ja klar, er kann es nicht lassen. Ich habe jetzt lange genug versucht das zu vermeiden, meine Geduld ist nun zu Ende. Meine Optionen ebenfalls, die hat Mr. Ego gerade höchstpersönlich vernichtet. Na gut, dann eben so.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="german" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/german/"/>
    
      <category term="writing" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bi
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/07/21/Bi/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/07/21/Bi/</id>
    <published>2016-07-20T23:23:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multilingualism" target="_blank" rel="external">BiLingual</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bipedalism" target="_blank" rel="external">BiPedual</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ambidexterity" target="_blank" rel="external">BiDextrous</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biphasic_and_polyphasic_sleep" target="_blank" rel="external">BiPhasic</a><br><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/bihemispheric" target="_blank" rel="external">BiHemispheric</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binocular_vision" target="_blank" rel="external">BiNocular</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bipolar_II_disorder" target="_blank" rel="external">BiPolar</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_sapiens" target="_blank" rel="external">BiNomial</a><br><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/biliteral" target="_blank" rel="external">BiLiteral</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bisexuality" target="_blank" rel="external">BiSexual</a><br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bidirectional" target="_blank" rel="external">BiDirectional</a><br><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/bicentral" target="_blank" rel="external">BiCentral</a></p><p>I am so damn <a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Category:English_words_prefixed_with_bi-" target="_blank" rel="external">Bi</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multilingualism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiLingual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bipedalism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiPedual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ambidexterity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiDextrous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biphasic_and_polyphasic_sleep&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiPhasic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/bihemispheric&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiHemispheric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binocular_vision&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiNocular&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bipolar_II_disorder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiPolar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_sapiens&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiNomial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/biliteral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiLiteral&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bisexuality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiSexual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bidirectional&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiDirectional&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/bicentral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;BiCentral&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am so damn &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Category:English_words_prefixed_with_bi-&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Bi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="writing" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Expect more German
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/05/26/Expect-more-German/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/05/26/Expect-more-German/</id>
    <published>2016-05-26T16:38:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the future, I will start writing posts in German.<br>This blog has always been about my opinions on things. I’ve used it to vent my rage and anger, as well as my fears. It’s been about my life, things I like and work on and an outlet for my poetry.</p><p>I chose to write in English because I like it. I write a lot of texts, mostly poetry, that I never make public.</p><p>Writing is always about my personal opinion and views on things. Lately, there has been a lot going on in Austria that I want to talk about. Using English for this seems kind of strange, I want my readers (which are very few, but who cares) to have it easy to follow the posts. I’ll also have to use a lot of German terms that I don’t want to translate because it’s a lot of work.</p><p>To sum it up, expect German posts. I’ll tag all posts with a language in the future and might add a menu to find them quickly.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;In the future, I will start writing posts in German.&lt;br&gt;This blog has always been about my opinions on things. I’ve used it to vent my rage and anger, as well as my fears. It’s been about my life, things I like and work on and an outlet for my poetry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I chose to write in English because I like it. I write a lot of texts, mostly poetry, that I never make public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing is always about my personal opinion and views on things. Lately, there has been a lot going on in Austria that I want to talk about. Using English for this seems kind of strange, I want my readers (which are very few, but who cares) to have it easy to follow the posts. I’ll also have to use a lot of German terms that I don’t want to translate because it’s a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How To: Gi zusammenlegen
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/04/12/How-To-Gi-zusammenlegen/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/04/12/How-To-Gi-zusammenlegen/</id>
    <published>2016-04-12T15:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T05:17:33.351Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich besitze derzeit 7 (oder 8?) Gis und werde oft gefragt wie man einen Gi so zusammen legen kann dass er ohne Falten transportiert werden kann.</p><p>Daher hier ein How-To in Bildern. Der Gi ist in diesem Fall absichtlich nicht gebügelt, wenn man ihn so eine Woche im Kleiderschrank aufbewahrt erledigt sich das von selbst.</p><p><img src="/images/23ba39675486e7d69bdbd8400208c974f7fe92cb.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Erst einmal alles sammeln. Jacke, Hose, Gürtel</p><p><img src="/images/c2f22851322b15a486cbc4acb7ff9a49cc406566.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Die Jacke ausbreiten und möglichst glatt streichen.</p><p><img src="/images/8bdef50031a638bd0f1400aaae9829ba722a0d55.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Danach die Hose zusammenfalten</p><p><img src="/images/feb225e187d08d463c94c7d2bfba9a62514bd6f3.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Die Hose wird nun mit dem Bund an den Kragen gelegt…</p><p><img src="/images/c016abb2f2b57acfc4746ac98df3d66071af3d41.jpg" alt=""></p><p>… und unten Bündig umgefalten.</p><p><img src="/images/8d2f22edc4e4f74775bb4b372dcb196849502a71.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Nun werden die Ärmel eingefalten so dass sie jeweils ca<br>1/3 der gesammten breite brauchen. Das Loch in der<br>Mitte ist also in etwa gleich lang wie jeder Ärmel.<br>Wie immer alles glatt streichen.</p><p><img src="/images/4d2c1e2128d74c4adc455fd3cbc9f0db255f7dd8.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Nun wird eine Seite umgefalten, Bündig zum anderen Ärmel</p><p><img src="/images/b790434c99170a4923da79f302907465ffb438f5.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Danach die 2. Seite. Wieder alles möglichst glatt streichen.</p><p><img src="/images/46acd95106f296fe844899f5537d420b1217e0db.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Das untere Ende bis zur Hälfte umfalten.</p><p><img src="/images/d091c637f888e1fc6fa3c304f0c9b60652c58e7e.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Nun wird der Gürtel gedrittelt…</p><p><img src="/images/8e775081dd3ac2534bad102edbbe40c6cd827a11.jpg" alt=""></p><p>… und in die mitte des Gis gelegt.</p><p><img src="/images/6fffa3a330f9386f90e0d6d5bca976b8070954c0.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Das untere Ende nach oben falten. Fertig.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Ich besitze derzeit 7 (oder 8?) Gis und werde oft gefragt wie man einen Gi so zusammen legen kann dass er ohne Falten transportiert werden kann.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daher hier ein How-To in Bildern. Der Gi ist in diesem Fall absichtlich nicht gebügelt, wenn man ihn so eine Woche im Kleiderschrank aufbewahrt erledigt sich das von selbst.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/23ba39675486e7d69bdbd8400208c974f7fe92cb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="german" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/german/"/>
    
      <category term="martial arts" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/martial-arts/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>1. Dan
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/04/12/1-Dan/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/04/12/1-Dan/</id>
    <published>2016-04-12T14:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich habe am 18.3.2016 erfolgreich meine Prüfung zum 1. Dan JuJitsu abgelegt.<br>Die Vorbereitungen haben mich und meinen Uke, <a href="https://plus.google.com/111298489202683658439" target="_blank" rel="external">+Lorenz Hammel</a> gute 3 Monate beansprucht.<br>Im Rahmen der Vorbereitung habe ich 70 Waza Ketten erarbeitet und auswendig gelernt. Ich habe dabei besonderes Augenmerk darauf gelegt Techniken nicht zu wiederholen. Es war mir noch nicht möglich alles zu Zählen aber ich schätze es sind gute 250 verschiedene Techniken.<br>Es handelt sich hier um das Ergebnis von ca 7 Jahren Training.</p><p>Mein Weg in der sanften Kunst ist dadurch aber alles andere als beendet. Jetzt geht es erst richtig los. Es ist an der Zeit mein Wissen noch weiter zu fächern und es an alle zukünftigen JuJitsuka weiter zu geben.</p><p><img src="/images/b4e84b4857f2d0d4f9c33644a381e6dc73219d23.jpg" alt=""></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Ich habe am 18.3.2016 erfolgreich meine Prüfung zum 1. Dan JuJitsu abgelegt.&lt;br&gt;Die Vorbereitungen haben mich und meinen Uke, &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/111298489202683658439&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;+Lorenz Hammel&lt;/a&gt; gute 3 Monate beansprucht.&lt;br&gt;Im Rahmen der Vorbereitung habe ich 70 Waza Ketten erarbeitet und auswendig gelernt. Ich habe dabei besonderes Augenmerk darauf gelegt Techniken nicht zu wiederholen. Es war mir noch nicht möglich alles zu Zählen aber ich schätze es sind gute 250 verschiedene Techniken.&lt;br&gt;Es handelt sich hier um das Ergebnis von ca 7 Jahren Training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mein Weg in der sanften Kunst ist dadurch aber alles andere als beendet. Jetzt geht es erst richtig los. Es ist an der Zeit mein Wissen noch weiter zu fächern und es an alle zukünftigen JuJitsuka weiter zu geben.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/b4e84b4857f2d0d4f9c33644a381e6dc73219d23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="german" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/german/"/>
    
      <category term="martial arts" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/martial-arts/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Poem: Be Who You Are
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/03/09/Poem-Be-Who-You-Are/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/03/09/Poem-Be-Who-You-Are/</id>
    <published>2016-03-09T22:06:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Be who you are she said.<br>Sounds so easy, is so hard.<br>It needs passion, it needs art.<br>Feeding on this beating heart.</p><p>How can you be what no one is?<br>Be it an angel or the beast.<br>No one tells and no one knows.<br>Depths inside that you don’t show.</p><p>I am what I am and I accept<br>whatever’s hiding in this depth.<br>If you don’t like it, so be it.<br>I lead my life how I see fit.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Be who you are she said.&lt;br&gt;Sounds so easy, is so hard.&lt;br&gt;It needs passion, it needs art.&lt;br&gt;Feeding on this beating heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can you be what no one is?&lt;br&gt;Be it an angel or the beast.&lt;br&gt;No one tells and no one knows.&lt;br&gt;Depths inside that you don’t show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am what I am and I accept&lt;br&gt;whatever’s hiding in this depth.&lt;br&gt;If you don’t like it, so be it.&lt;br&gt;I lead my life how I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="writing" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Strange Mistress
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/02/06/A-Strange-Mistress/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2016/02/06/A-Strange-Mistress/</id>
    <published>2016-02-06T02:35:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Feelings are strange. Sometimes they just jump into your face out of nowhere, stay there for a few moments and then leave again. The hard part is to deal with these moments.</p><p>I haven’t written anything in the last few months. Then suddenly, along comes an old feeling that feels a lot less intense than it did in my last life. Looks like I changed a lot.</p><p>Anyway, I decided I’d write about it. It’s not a particularly good text and I just wrote it down the way it fell out of my head. It’s not as refined as most of my texts which usually take a few days to a few weeks to be finished, if ever.</p><p>Loneliness, a strange mistress.</p><p>Unseen she’s there, unfelt she stares.<br>Unheard she tells, she whispers and yells.</p><p>It’s been awhile I’ve been with her.<br>Can’t say at all that I missed her.</p><p>Just sits right there and stares at you.<br>Has nothing better than this to do.</p><p>The tainted smirk that’s on her face<br>keeps telling me I lost this race.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Feelings are strange. Sometimes they just jump into your face out of nowhere, stay there for a few moments and then leave again. The hard part is to deal with these moments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven’t written anything in the last few months. Then suddenly, along comes an old feeling that feels a lot less intense than it did in my last life. Looks like I changed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I decided I’d write about it. It’s not a particularly good text and I just wrote it down the way it fell out of my head. It’s not as refined as most of my texts which usually take a few days to a few weeks to be finished, if ever.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="writing" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>FCS Level 1
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/11/30/FCS-Level-1/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/11/30/FCS-Level-1/</id>
    <published>2015-11-30T10:50:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich habe am 3. November 2015 erfolgreich die FCS Level 1 Prüfung abgelegt.<br>Super vielen dank an meinen wirklich guten Freund Thilo Würkner der mich Trainiert hat. Ohne dich hätte ich das nicht.</p><p><img src="/images/6680812e2d8f8873b4160474aaeb405e6fe793cb.jpg" alt=""></p><p>v.L.n.R.: Eugen Dahm, Daniel Neuretter, Ray Dionaldo, Thilo Würkner, Ich</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Ich habe am 3. November 2015 erfolgreich die FCS Level 1 Prüfung abgelegt.&lt;br&gt;Super vielen dank an meinen wirklich guten Freund Thilo Würkner der mich Trainiert hat. Ohne dich hätte ich das nicht.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/6680812e2d8f8873b4160474aaeb405e6fe793cb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;v.L.n.R.: Eugen Dahm, Daniel Neuretter, Ray Dionaldo, Thilo Würkner, Ich&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="german" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/german/"/>
    
      <category term="martial arts" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/martial-arts/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ist das JuJitsu?
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/11/30/Ist-das-JuJitsu/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/11/30/Ist-das-JuJitsu/</id>
    <published>2015-11-30T10:01:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich habe in der letzten Zeit einiges an Lehrgängen besucht. Wie jedes Jahr.<br>Dabei waren heuer: <a href="http://www.goryu-jujitsu.at/2015/03/tatsu-tora-kai-5-osterlehrgang-mit-dr.html" target="_blank" rel="external">5. Osterlehrgang mit Josef Linder</a>, <a href="http://www.goryu-jujitsu.at/2015/06/goryu-jujitsu-in-ansbach.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Budo Pfingstlehrgang Ansbach</a>, <a href="http://www.jjvoe.at/content/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=326:pinkafeld-gedenklehrgang-franz-strauss-05-11072015&amp;catid=80:aktuelles&amp;Itemid=53" target="_blank" rel="external">Pinkafeld Gedenklehrgang für Franz Strauss</a>, FCS Germany Gathering, FCS Austria Lehrgang und natürlich auch wieder der Kampfkunst/Ich hab Spaß mit Freunden - Urlaub in Göstling.</p><p><img src="/images/dad5ed22a401814c32030c41442825b74a05cf7b.jpg" alt=""></p><p>FCS Germany Gathering.<br>Hier irgendwo versteckt:<br>Ray Dionaldo<br>Wilfried Harloff<br>Tim Blaschke<br>René Zeller<br>Thilo Würkner<br>Daniel Neuretter<br>Ich</p><p>Am FCS Austria Lehrgang konnte ich unter den Augen von Ray Dionaldo die Level 1 Prüfung im FCS ablegen. Fehlen nur noch 4.</p><p>Natürlich gebe ich mein Wissen weiter. Auf den FCS Lehrgängen wurde das FCS Panantukan Template gezeigt, welches ich natürlich meinem Verein nicht vorenthalten wollte.</p><p>Dabei kam die Frage auf: Was hat das mit JuJitsu zu tun? Gute Frage. Meiner Meinung nach sehr viel, aber erstmal meine persönliche Antwort auf ein paar abgewandelte Versionen der Frage:</p><h3 id="Ist-das-klassisches-JuJitsu"><a href="#Ist-das-klassisches-JuJitsu" class="headerlink" title="Ist das klassisches JuJitsu?"></a>Ist das klassisches JuJitsu?</h3><p>Nein, denn einen Samurai in voller Rüstung sieben mal in sehr kurzer Zeit zu schlagen wäre absolut sinnlos - außer man steht auf gebrochene Hände.</p><h3 id="Ist-das-modernes-JuJitsu"><a href="#Ist-das-modernes-JuJitsu" class="headerlink" title="Ist das modernes JuJitsu?"></a>Ist das modernes JuJitsu?</h3><p>Soweit ich sagen kann Nein. Geschlagen wird zwar im JuJitsu zwar aber bestimmt nicht in einem Panantukan Ellbow Cover und sicher nicht so dass man dabei auch gleich zwei Messer halten kann.</p><p><img src="/images/77bd93f3ae057f55bcb7b65455524d2924dcf043.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Einer der Panantukan Blocks.<br>Das ist <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Grislee" target="_blank" rel="external">Christian Metzner</a>.<br>Super Trainer und immer spaßig.<br>Er ist <a href="http://www.kampfkunstzentrum.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">hier</a> zu finden. Schaut vorbei.</p><h3 id="Ist-das-GoRyu-JuJitsu"><a href="#Ist-das-GoRyu-JuJitsu" class="headerlink" title="Ist das GoRyu JuJitsu?"></a>Ist das GoRyu JuJitsu?</h3><p>Auf jeden Fall. Wir definieren uns als moderne Selbstverteidigung auf der Basis von JuJitsu. Wenn man sich mit Selbstverteidigung beschäftigt und nur in seinem eigenen System bleibt ohne jemals über den Tellerrand zu blicken hat man schon verloren. Man wird automatisch betriebsblind. Warum sonst würde ich FCS und Gracie Jiu-Jitsu Trainieren?<br>Natürlich muss man alles in sein eigenes System einbinden. GoRyu hat kein festes System, wir sind keine Stilrichtung und können per Definition auch keine werden. Jeder bei uns muss seinen eigenen Stil finden.</p><h3 id="Also-was-Jetzt-Ist-es-JuJitsu-oder-nicht"><a href="#Also-was-Jetzt-Ist-es-JuJitsu-oder-nicht" class="headerlink" title="Also was Jetzt? Ist es JuJitsu oder nicht?"></a>Also was Jetzt? Ist es JuJitsu oder nicht?</h3><p>Kommt ganz darauf an was JuJitsu für denjenigen bedeutet der die Frage stellt.</p><p>Es ist auf jeden Fall ein Teil meines persönlichen JuJitsu Stils. Wie definiert sich der? Darüber denke ich schon länger nach. Auf jeden Fall dadurch dass er sich ständig verändert und weiterentwickelt. Stillstand bedeutet Rückschritt, auch in der Kampfkunst. Ich arbeite mit Hebeln und Würgern, Bodenkampf, Schockschlägen und mit Waffen. Würfe eher selten weil sie mir - zur Zeit - nicht reinpassen. Ich weiche gerne aus und mache so gut wie nie harte Blocks, auch wenn das mit meinem Körperbau gehen würde. Passt halt einfach zu mir. Mein Stil ist mein eigener und er passt. Dazu gehört auch Panantukan. Auch wenn ich nicht gerne Zuschlage.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Ich habe in der letzten Zeit einiges an Lehrgängen besucht. Wie jedes Jahr.&lt;br&gt;Dabei waren heuer: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goryu-jujitsu.at/2015/03/tatsu-tora-kai-5-osterlehrgang-mit-dr.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;5. Osterlehrgang mit Josef Linder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goryu-jujitsu.at/2015/06/goryu-jujitsu-in-ansbach.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Budo Pfingstlehrgang Ansbach&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jjvoe.at/content/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=326:pinkafeld-gedenklehrgang-franz-strauss-05-11072015&amp;amp;catid=80:aktuelles&amp;amp;Itemid=53&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Pinkafeld Gedenklehrgang für Franz Strauss&lt;/a&gt;, FCS Germany Gathering, FCS Austria Lehrgang und natürlich auch wieder der Kampfkunst/Ich hab Spaß mit Freunden - Urlaub in Göstling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dad5ed22a401814c32030c41442825b74a05cf7b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FCS Germany Gathering.&lt;br&gt;Hier irgendwo versteckt:&lt;br&gt;Ray Dionaldo&lt;br&gt;Wilfried Harloff&lt;br&gt;Tim Blaschke&lt;br&gt;René Zeller&lt;br&gt;Thilo Würkner&lt;br&gt;Daniel Neuretter&lt;br&gt;Ich&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="german" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/german/"/>
    
      <category term="martial arts" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/martial-arts/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Poem: The Devil is Moving
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/07/11/Poem-The-Devil-is-Moving/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/07/11/Poem-The-Devil-is-Moving/</id>
    <published>2015-07-11T19:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The devil is moving, it’s out of control.<br>It broke my heart now it is after my soul.<br>It made me lose all my self control and forced me to endure the worst of it all.</p><p>It made me a devil I never wanted to know.<br>Took me to a dark place in my very own soul.<br>One day I broke out of it’s tight control started a new life without all this sorrow.</p><p>The devil is moving but now I’m not alone.<br>I found an angel, a very kind soul.<br>It showed me that there is still so much more to know, feelings to share and wonders to behold.</p><p>An untainted being without the control,<br>over my mind, my body and soul.<br>Accepting my life without prejudice or scorn but showing it’s kindness it’s trust and it’s glow.</p><p>The devil I knew is gone and within all<br>The horrors that came just after the fall.<br>I learned to hold on to the good things I know, a daughter, a home and the people I know.</p><p>The devil is moving, launching another attack.<br>But this time I’m not the target for its wrath.<br>A new life can start and feelings now grow, for the angel of kindness, savior of my soul.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The devil is moving, it’s out of control.&lt;br&gt;It broke my heart now it is after my soul.&lt;br&gt;It made me lose all my self control and forced me to endure the worst of it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It made me a devil I never wanted to know.&lt;br&gt;Took me to a dark place in my very own soul.&lt;br&gt;One day I broke out of it’s tight control started a new life without all this sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The devil is moving but now I’m not alone.&lt;br&gt;I found an angel, a very kind soul.&lt;br&gt;It showed me that there is still so much more to know, feelings to share and wonders to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="writing" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/writing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Strange Times
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/07/02/Strange-Times/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/07/02/Strange-Times/</id>
    <published>2015-07-02T10:14:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m having a rather strange year. Very different to the last one.</p><p>While the first half was terrible, in fact the darkest time of my whole life, but the recent past is the complete opposite. I can’t remember that I ever had such a positive attitude. My usual mindset was pessimistic and often depressed.</p><p>Now, this is a little paradox because I’m in the middle of getting divorced. But I realized it’s the right decision. When this is sorted out, I can start working on a new future. If I can be bothered that is. Right now it is good to just live happy, healthy and not have plans.</p><p>I am still getting used to feel good. Sounds strange right? But really, I actually never was this way. Maybe a few days or hours at a time, but never this long and never so <strong>deep</strong>. I can’t even tell if this is the way life is supposed to be, I never experienced this.</p><p>I am a totally different person now. Most of my world views are still the same but my general attitude against life is the other way around. Right now life is a joy not a drag.</p><p>Now, this post might ring a few alarm bells for some people. Chill and let me explain something: Compared to my manic episodes, I can’t really be bothered to work around the clock. In fact it’s the opposite. I train a little bit more, but only in the weeks when I don’t have my daughter. When she is around I don’t have time for that. I learn too many languages at once right now. I noticed that and already consider cutting back. Personally, I don’t think I’m manic at the moment. Buy keep your eyes open, just in case ;-)</p><p><img src="/images/5a19e6566abf7c86d6effa830fde3a6ca33f782e.jpg" alt=""></p><p>See that? That’s me being happy.</p><p>I need a witness to my life it wasn’t this way all the time</p><p><strong>– Mindless Self Indulgence</strong>, Witness</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I’m having a rather strange year. Very different to the last one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the first half was terrible, in fact the darkest time of my whole life, but the recent past is the complete opposite. I can’t remember that I ever had such a positive attitude. My usual mindset was pessimistic and often depressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, this is a little paradox because I’m in the middle of getting divorced. But I realized it’s the right decision. When this is sorted out, I can start working on a new future. If I can be bothered that is. Right now it is good to just live happy, healthy and not have plans.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="recovery" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/recovery/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Poem: The Wild Blossom
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/07/01/Poem-The-Wild-Blossom/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/07/01/Poem-The-Wild-Blossom/</id>
    <published>2015-07-01T06:26:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s just a small and fragile thing.<br>Was born in an unusual spring.<br>It yearns for summer’s tender wind.<br>It does not care what autumn brings.<br>The winter made this peaceful thing.</p><p>And then the blossom starts to sing.<br>Oh life, you are a wondrous thing!<br>Sun on my leaves, now does begin<br>another tale of grass and green.<br>Of how I love this tender stream,<br>the raindrops running down my skin.</p><p>Now the wild blossom grows in size.<br>It is still young but might arise,<br>might be the mightiest in size!<br>Or could just grow to normal size.</p><p>The gardener has to be tender.<br>The blossom needs a generous spender.<br>One that cares and will defend her.<br>It also needs a lot of time.<br>And maybe then, the bloom will shine.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;It’s just a small and fragile thing.&lt;br&gt;Was born in an unusual spring.&lt;br&gt;It yearns for summer’s tender wind.&lt;br&gt;It does not care what autumn brings.&lt;br&gt;The winter made this peaceful thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then the blossom starts to sing.&lt;br&gt;Oh life, you are a wondrous thing!&lt;br&gt;Sun on my leaves, now does begin&lt;br&gt;another tale of grass and green.&lt;br&gt;Of how I love this tender stream,&lt;br&gt;the raindrops running down my skin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the wild blossom grows in size.&lt;br&gt;It is still young but might arise,&lt;br&gt;might be the mightiest in size!&lt;br&gt;Or could just grow to normal size.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="writing" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/writing/"/>
    
      <category term="recovery" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/recovery/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Moving on
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/06/22/Moving-on/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/06/22/Moving-on/</id>
    <published>2015-06-22T17:28:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So much has changed. The last one and a half years were hard but I pulled through.<br>I learned a lot about life. Albeit the price for this learning experience was too high.<br>Our relationship broke, we will get divorced. I think it was broken beyond repair since last year’s August.<br>I just could not accept it. Now I can - I’m ready to move on.<br>I learned a lot. How to live alone, how to trust less, how it feels to lose all of your future against your will.<br>How it feels when one of your closest friends betrays you in ways you can’t really imagine and can’t ever forgive nor forget.</p><p>I learned that nothing in life is as important as friends and family that help you through dark times. I would definitely not have made it without you guys.<br>My friends who provided shelter, moral support and drinking buddies. The people that would listen to my endless rants and take my ailments serious.<br>You provided help in the darkest time of my life. I am forever in your dept. I don’t take all this for granted.</p><p>This is a short updated, compared to the last few posts. But it’s one that is not written in a depressed mindset for once.<br>In fact, I have never felt so comfortable in my own skin before.</p><p><img src="/images/81f1f66d1a886b964ce233dc1e316f23d7447c9a.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Keep it real.</p><p>The hardest day in my whole damn life was the day that I said good bye.</p><p><strong>– Digital Summer</strong>, This Time</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;So much has changed. The last one and a half years were hard but I pulled through.&lt;br&gt;I learned a lot about life. Albeit the price for this learning experience was too high.&lt;br&gt;Our relationship broke, we will get divorced. I think it was broken beyond repair since last year’s August.&lt;br&gt;I just could not accept it. Now I can - I’m ready to move on.&lt;br&gt;I learned a lot. How to live alone, how to trust less, how it feels to lose all of your future against your will.&lt;br&gt;How it feels when one of your closest friends betrays you in ways you can’t really imagine and can’t ever forgive nor forget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learned that nothing in life is as important as friends and family that help you through dark times. I would definitely not have made it without you guys.&lt;br&gt;My friends who provided shelter, moral support and drinking buddies. The people that would listen to my endless rants and take my ailments serious.&lt;br&gt;You provided help in the darkest time of my life. I am forever in your dept. I don’t take all this for granted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a short updated, compared to the last few posts. But it’s one that is not written in a depressed mindset for once.&lt;br&gt;In fact, I have never felt so comfortable in my own skin before.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="recovery" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/recovery/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>This blog needs an update
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/06/21/This-blog-needs-an-update/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/06/21/This-blog-needs-an-update/</id>
    <published>2015-06-21T17:29:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>And I will write one in the near future.</p><p>I’m fine. A lot has changed. Life is a roller coaster ride.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;And I will write one in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m fine. A lot has changed. Life is a roller coaster ride.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What the hell have I done?
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/03/18/What-the-hell-have-I-done/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/03/18/What-the-hell-have-I-done/</id>
    <published>2015-03-18T10:57:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I couldn’t control myself. I had another emotional breakdown and ruined a lot again. I have no idea if this damage can ever be repaired.<br>It’s the first time that my sickness got me. I hate myself for not thinking longer before speaking. I wasn’t myself and let my broken parts cause havoc.</p><p>This might have been the biggest mistake ever. I have no idea if this problem is fixable, and I am the only one to blame.</p><p>I hate myself right now. I hate my disease. I cause chaos again, in a time where chaos can ruin everything. I messed with our stability. I am stupid and unstable and I did not want all of this.</p><p>I have no idea what to do. Life can be a bitch.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I couldn’t control myself. I had another emotional breakdown and ruined a lot again. I have no idea if this damage can ever be repaired.&lt;br&gt;It’s the first time that my sickness got me. I hate myself for not thinking longer before speaking. I wasn’t myself and let my broken parts cause havoc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This might have been the biggest mistake ever. I have no idea if this problem is fixable, and I am the only one to blame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hate myself right now. I hate my disease. I cause chaos again, in a time where chaos can ruin everything. I messed with our stability. I am stupid and unstable and I did not want all of this.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="relapse" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/relapse/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Comfort
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/03/11/Comfort/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/03/11/Comfort/</id>
    <published>2015-03-11T14:57:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you find comfort in strange places.</p><p>I reached a new low last week and came out faster and stronger than ever before.</p><p>Therapy seems to work better than I acknowledged.</p><p>I built a safe inside of me. It’s an imagination technique that I learned recently. It holds emotions and thoughts that I cannot handle at the moment.</p><p>I put a lot of stuff in there. Things about my past. Things I did wrong. Things from the present.</p><p>Last Friday I also put my broken heart in there. It is now safely locked away and I can start to move forward.</p><p>I made the conscious decision to do that. I will no longer let my love rule over me. I stop that now, before it overshadows everything that I am.</p><p>I finally quit love. It’s hard but then again it’s easier than I thought. I let go. This does not mean that I don’t have hope for my marriage, but there was no point in clinging to something so horribly broken.</p><p>Nicole was not ready for a new start. I can’t blame her. She was furious with me, as she should be. I was mad about some of her actions. So I had to let her go, for my own good and for her sanity. We made a mess out of each other in the last year and especially in the last two months. It is a very sad story. I told parts of it already, no point in going over it again.</p><p>We broke up. I did. It’s time to leave this mess behind. It does not need to be cleaned up now, it’s over.</p><p>Paradoxically, this changed everything in a way I never expected. A huge mountain of stress and sadness simply evaporated in our lives. I could literally see this happening within a few hours. Now, we are closer to each other than in the last year, maybe even longer.</p><p>We are currently split up. And yet something even more huge has changed. I think this time we have a real chance.</p><p>Our marriage might heal, but it does not have to. I don’t feel compelled to fix it anymore and I think Nicole neither. I would like this to happen but if it doesn’t, we’ll go separate ways, in peace.</p><p>Our lives are entangled anyway because of our daughter. But all the hard feelings are gone, at least for me.</p><p>I feel really good.</p><p><img src="/images/cbf6138ab62500ba6f068e3898b7673f97e42e41.jpg" alt=""></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Sometimes you find comfort in strange places.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I reached a new low last week and came out faster and stronger than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therapy seems to work better than I acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="recovery" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/recovery/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Eleven years
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/03/02/Eleven-years/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/03/02/Eleven-years/</id>
    <published>2015-03-01T23:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So this is it. After eleven years, I am single again. We had ten wonderful years and one troubled one. We tried getting back on course. First I was not ready, then she wasn’t, still isn’t. I just broke up with the person I love more than anything else (My daughter excluded of course. Alice trumps everything, all the time).</p><p>We decided to stop having a relationship for the coming month. Nicole needs to get her life together and this is the only way in which I can help. I trade my happiness for her well being. Love makes you do crazy things.</p><p>Nicole might be ready tomorrow. Or in a week or a year. And her decision might change just as quick. She is currently so messed up that there is simply no point in carrying on. I know because I tried. I gave my best but fixing a relationship is not a solo project.</p><p>I won’t move out, we still live together but without the security or bonds of a relationship. I said goodbye to my old life today. When I return home I will most likely be a different person.</p><p>The good thing is that I already learned to adapt to life quickly. That’s mainly due to therapy. I am preparing for a more lonely life and I know I will manage. It won’t be nice. Reality is a harsh, cold and lonely place. And the universe does not give a shit about what you had to endure.</p><p>Nicole, I hope you learn to see a future again. I really want to be a part of it.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;So this is it. After eleven years, I am single again. We had ten wonderful years and one troubled one. We tried getting back on course. First I was not ready, then she wasn’t, still isn’t. I just broke up with the person I love more than anything else (My daughter excluded of course. Alice trumps everything, all the time).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided to stop having a relationship for the coming month. Nicole needs to get her life together and this is the only way in which I can help. I trade my happiness for her well being. Love makes you do crazy things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicole might be ready tomorrow. Or in a week or a year. And her decision might change just as quick. She is currently so messed up that there is simply no point in carrying on. I know because I tried. I gave my best but fixing a relationship is not a solo project.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="recovery" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/recovery/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Love
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/02/28/Love/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/02/28/Love/</id>
    <published>2015-02-28T12:50:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Love will break.<br>Sometimes it is fixable.<br>Sometimes it has to be replaced.</p><p>We were supposed to take on the world.</p><p>– <strong>Avatar, </strong>Torn Apart</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Love will break.&lt;br&gt;Sometimes it is fixable.&lt;br&gt;Sometimes it has to be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to take on the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Avatar, &lt;/strong&gt;Torn Apart&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Agony
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/02/27/Agony/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/02/27/Agony/</id>
    <published>2015-02-27T08:56:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m spent.</p><p>I’m done.</p><p>Happiness has gone.</p><p>My life, a heap of shards.</p><p>Cut into pieces no one wants.</p><p>The ocean swallows me.</p><p>A stone without a shore.</p><p>The fire did not burn for me.</p><p>So much life in misery.</p><p>I drown in tears I cry for her.</p><p>I shout out loud and want it gone.</p><p>Can’t take the agony and misery.</p><p>No talks, no life, no end to see.</p><p>Old though are taking over me.</p><p>Death,my beloved enemy.</p><p>One day we will meet and see,</p><p>there is no place for me to flee.</p><p>Kicked when down and thrown around.</p><p>Hurting in this moment, just to see,</p><p>I gave my best and yet ain’t free.</p><p>Demons lurking inside me.</p><p>Another bitter tragedy.</p><p>Suicidal tendencies. Clean up the mess.</p><p>Please crazy diamond shine on me.</p><p>Are we all just torn apart?</p><p>Kill myself to make everybody pay.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I’m spent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Happiness has gone.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="relapse" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/relapse/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Betrayal
</title>
    <link href="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/02/23/Betrayal/"/>
    <id>https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/2015/02/23/Betrayal/</id>
    <published>2015-02-23T11:29:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-10T03:49:57.534Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From all the feelings that I ever felt, betrayal is the hardest to stomach.</p><p><a href="http://blog.meredrica.org/2015/02/my-condition-home-diagnosis-and-bad.html" target="_blank" rel="external">I thought things were getting better.</a> Was I naive again? I can’t tell.</p><p>Nicole still sees him, has daily contact. <a href="https://twitter.com/countsickness" target="_blank" rel="external">Thomas Handschuh</a>, a guy I once counted to my best friends, and whom I have never named as one of the sources of my misery, is still trying to botch my life. He just can’t get the fuck out of my way and let me try to heal my family. I wanted to have him back as a friend. Not anymore.</p><p>I tried to support my wife in every possible way. I understood that she is hurting. But yesterday I figured out she is still in close contact with him. Heck, he was even in my flat. Sees her when she is at shows, goes to her performances at the theater and the party afterwards. While I am at home taking care of our sick daughter.</p><p>I have never felt more betrayed than now. Bring on <a href="http://blog.meredrica.org/2015/01/meredrica-great-destroyer.html" target="_blank" rel="external">The Great Destroyer</a>.</p><p>This time, it’s the last chance I am willing to grant to Nicole. I set her an ultimatum to cut ties with him completely. Today. If this doesn’t happen,it’s over. Simple as that.<br>I learned I can live without her, but I want her in my life. But not at all costs and not on the pretext of betrayal.</p><p><img src="/images/83a80ac3c2c3c97ec9525453860cb8978634419b.ashx?multiverseid=6567&amp;type=card" alt=""></p><p>I was over this shit. I did not have hard feelings for anybody. Gave my best to maintain a very positive attitude and outlook for the future. Most of this was destroyed last night.</p><p>This time, it were not my own actions that pushed me back to the dark side. I am not to blame.</p><p>I am not willing to continue this way. I have no idea what will come out of this. But I will survive.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;From all the feelings that I ever felt, betrayal is the hardest to stomach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.meredrica.org/2015/02/my-condition-home-diagnosis-and-bad.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;I thought things were getting better.&lt;/a&gt; Was I naive again? I can’t tell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicole still sees him, has daily contact. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/countsickness&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Thomas Handschuh&lt;/a&gt;, a guy I once counted to my best friends, and whom I have never named as one of the sources of my misery, is still trying to botch my life. He just can’t get the fuck out of my way and let me try to heal my family. I wanted to have him back as a friend. Not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/life/"/>
    
      <category term="english" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/english/"/>
    
      <category term="recovery" scheme="https://meredrica.github.io/hexo-theme-material-image/tags/recovery/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
